Hello, I'm Jay, and in this lesson,
大家好 我叫 Jay
we'll be talking about one of
在这节课 我们将讨论
the most important innovations in deep learning in the last few years, Attention.
在过去几年内深度学习领域最重要的创新之一 即注意力
Attention started out in the field of
注意力一开始出现在计算机视觉领域
computer vision as an attempt to mimic human perception.
用来尝试模仿人类感知力
This is a quote from a paper on Visual Attention from 2014.
这段话摘自 2014 年的一篇视觉注意力论文
It says that, "One important property of human perception is that one does
“人类感知力的一个重要特性是”
not tend to process a scene in its entirety all at once.
“我们不需要同时处理整个场景”
Instead humans focus attention selectively on parts of
“相反 我们选择性地将注意力集中在视觉空间的某些部分”
the visual space to acquire information when and where it's needed,
“以便在合适的时间和地点获取信息”
and then combine information from different fixations over
“然后将一段时间内来自不同视点的信息相结合”
time to build up an internal representation of the entire scene,
“在大脑内对整个场景构建表示结果”
guiding future eye movement and decision-making."
“为后续眼球运动和决策制定提供指导”
What that means is that when we look at a scene in our daily lives,
这段话的含义是 当我们在日常生活中看到某个场景时
our brains do not just process a visual snapshot all at once.
我们的大脑并不是一次性处理一个视觉快照
Instead we selectively focus on different parts of the image,
而是选择性地侧重于图像的不同部分
and we sequentially collect and process that visual information over time.
并且逐渐按顺序收集和处理这些视觉信息
Say, for example, you're shopping in a shopping mall.
例如 你在商场中购物
Now, the footage that we're going to see here is from an eye-tracking device.
我们将看到的视频录像是由眼球追踪设备拍摄的
If you haven't seen those before,
如果你没见过这种设备的话 解释下
it's a device that records both what's in front of
它是一种同时录制眼前景象
you and it also records your eye movement.
和眼球运动的设备
Then, we can overlay these two recordings so we can have
我们可以将这些视频相结合
an idea of where you were looking at each time in the video.
判断出在视频中的每个时刻 你看向什么位置
So, what we're seeing here is footage from a person wearing the eye-tracking device,
我们看到的这段录像是佩戴眼球追踪设备的人录制的片段
where the orange circle is highlighting where the person is looking at each moment.
橘色圆圈表示每时每刻此人看到的位置
So, we can see attention in general visual perception,
我们可以在普通的视觉感知中发现注意力
but you can also see it in reading and trying to process text one word at a time.
还可以在阅读中发现注意力 即每次尝试处理文本中的一个单词
This type of device is used,
这种设备可以用于
for example, in user experience testing.
用户体验测试
If you wanted to build a user interface for an app or website and you
如果你想为应用或网站构建用户界面
wanted to track if the most important things are
并且想检测最重要的元素
actually grabbing the attention of the users,
是否吸引了用户的注意力
and since that's how humans tend to understand a visual picture sequentially over time,
因为这是人类在一段时间内按顺序理解视觉图片的方式
the idea from computer vision researchers was to try to
计算机视觉研究人员希望找到一种方法
adopt a method that does that for computer vision models.
使计算机视觉模型能够这么操作
In machine learning, attention methods give us
在机器学习中 注意力方法
a mechanism for adding selective focus into a machine learning model.
使我们能够向机器学习模型中添加选择性焦点
Typically, one that does its processing sequentially.
通常是按序列进行处理
Attention is a concept that powers up some of
注意力为某些性能最佳的模型提供了支持
the best performing models spanning both natural language processing and computer vision.
包括自然语言处理和计算机视觉模型
These models include: neural machine translation,
这些模型包括神经机器翻译
image captioning, speech recognition,
图像说明 语音识别
and text summarization, as well as others.
和文本摘要等等
Take image classification in captioning as an example.
举个图像说明的例子
Before the use of attention,
在使用注意力技巧之前
convolutional neural networks were able to classify
卷积神经网络能够通过查看整个图像
images by looking at the whole image and outputting a class label.
对图像进行分类并输出分类标签
But not all of this image is necessary to produce that classification;
但是为了生成分类标签 并非整个图像都有必要查看
only some of these pixels are needed to identify a bird,
只需查看部分像素就能判断这是个鸟类图像
and attention came out of the desire to attend to these most important pixels.
这时候 注意力就派上用场了 可以处理这些最重要的像素
Now, not only that,
此外
but attention also improved our ability to describe images with
注意力还提高了
full sentences by focusing on
我们使用完整句子描述图像的能力
different parts of the image as we generate our output sentence.
因为我们在生成句子时 会侧重于图像的不同部分
Attention achieved its rise to fame, however,
注意力变得火热起来
from how useful it became in tasks like neural machine translation.
它在神经机器翻译等任务中变得非常实用
As sequence to sequence models started to exhibit impressive results,
但是 随着序列到序列模型开始取得显著成果
they were held back by certain limitations that made it
它们受到了一些限制
difficult for them to process long sentences, for example.
导致难以处理长句子等
Classic sequence to sequence models, without attention,
没有注意力的传统序列到序列模型
have to look at the original sentence that you want to translate one time
需要一次性查看要翻译的原始句子
and then use that entire input to produce every single small outputted work.
然后利用整个输入信息生成所有单个小的输出结果
Attention, however, allows the model to look at
但是 注意力使模型能够查看
this small relevant parts of the input as you generate the output over time.
输入的相对小部分并逐渐生成输出结果
When attention was incorporated in sequence to sequence models,
当注意力被引入序列到序列模型后
they became the state of the art in neural machine translation.
这些模型成为了先进的神经机器翻译模型
This is what like Google to adopt neural machine translation with
因此 在 2016 年末 Google 将具有注意力的神经机器翻译
attention as the translation engine for Google translate in the end of 2016.
用作 Google 翻译的翻译引擎
In this lesson, we'll look at how attention works and how and where it can be applied.
在这节课 我们将了解注意力的原理 以及如何及在何处应用注意力